omronhealthcare.com 2018-12-14

# Privacy Policy

**Omron Healthcare Online Privacy Policy**   
**Updated October 12, 2018**

Omron Healthcare, Inc. (“Omron Healthcare,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) values your privacy. In this Privacy Policy (“Policy”), we describe how we collect, use, and disclose information that we obtain about visitors to our website OmronHealthcare.com (the “Site”) and how we use and disclose that information. This Policy applies only to information we collect at and through the Site. Some of our Omron affiliated sites and services, such as Omron.com and Omron247.com, and our mobile applications, are governed by their own separate privacy policies. Additionally, our online store is operated by our online store service provider, as is subject to a separate privacy policy and terms of sale provided at the online store site.

By visiting the Site or using any of the services available on our Site, you agree that your personal information will be handled as described in this Policy. Your use of our Site or services, and any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Use, including any applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes. The Omron Healthcare Terms of Use are incorporated by reference into this Policy.

**The Information We Collect About You**  
**Information We Collect Directly From You**  
**Information We Collect Automatically**  
**How We Use Your Information**  
**How We Share Your Information**  
**Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms**  
**Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies**  
**Third Party Analytics**  
**Cross-Device Use**  
**Do-Not-Track**  
**Third-Party Ad Networks**  
**User Generated Content**  
**Third-Party Links**  
**Information Crossing Borders**  
**Security of My Personal Information**  
**Access To My Personal Information**  
**What Choices Do I Have Regarding Use of My Personal Information?**  
**Children Under 13**  
**Special Information for California Consumers**  
**Contact Us**  
**Changes to this Policy**

**The Information We Collect About You**  
We collect information about you directly from you and from third parties, as well as automatically through your use of our Site.

**Information We Collect Directly From You**  
The information we collect from you depends on how you use the Site and services. If you register a product or sign up for email, we will collect your name, email address, phone number, physical address, and your product information. We also collect information about you when you contact us, including your name, email address, contact information, and the products or services you are inquiring about.

**Information We Collect Automatically**  
We and our third party service providers automatically collect the following information about your use of our Site through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies: your domain name; your browser type and operating system; web pages you view; links you click; your IP address; the length of time you visit or use our Site; and the referring URL, or the webpage that led you to our Site. We may combine this information with other information that we have collected about you, including the personal information we collect from you. Please see the section “Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms” below for more information.

**How We Use Your Information**  
We use your information, including your personal information, for the following purposes:

  * To provide our Site services to you, to communicate with you about your use of our Site and services, to respond to your inquiries, to fulfill your orders, and for other customer service purposes.
  * To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to you, to offer location customization, and personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize your experiences while using the Site.
  * For marketing and promotional purposes, to the extent permitted by law and, where required, with your consent. For example, we and our third party partners may use your information, such as your email address, to send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or to otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest you, including information about third party products and services. We also may use the information that we learn about you to assist us in advertising our services on third party websites.
  * To better understand how users access and use our Site and services, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, in order to improve our Site and services and respond to user desires and preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes.
  * To communicate with you about and administer our contests, sweepstakes, and other promotions.
  * To administer surveys and questionnaires.
  * To authenticate your identity.
  * To allow you to participate in our contests, and to administer those contests.
  * To monitor your compliance with any of your agreements with us.
  * To manage or transfer our assets or liabilities, for example in the case of an actual or potential acquisition, disposition or merger.
  * To collect debts owed to us. To comply with legal obligations, as part of our general business operations, and for other business administration purposes.
  * Where we believe necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or violations of our Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy.

**How We Share Your Information**  
We may share your information, including personal information, as follows:

  * _Site Visitors._ If you post content or product reviews on the Site, we will share your user name, demographic information, and your content with all Site visitors.
  * _Affiliates_ We may disclose the information we collect from you to our affiliates or subsidiaries; however, if we do so, their use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information will be subject to this Policy.
  * _Service Providers_ We may disclose the information we collect from you to third party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform functions on our behalf.
  * _Third Parties_ We may disclose information to third parties so they may send you information about their products and services.

We may also share information in the following circumstances:

  * _Business Transfers._ If we are, or may be, acquired by or merged with another company, if some or substantially all of our assets are or may be transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the information we have collected from you to the other company.
  * _In Response to Legal Process._ We also may disclose the information we collect from you in order to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena.
  * _To Protect Us and Others._ We also may disclose the information we collect from you where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use or this Policy, or as evidence in litigation in which Omron Healthcare is involved.
  * _Aggregate and De-Identified Information._ We may share aggregate or de-identified information about users with third parties for marketing, advertising, research or similar purposes.

**Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms**  
We and our third party service providers use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Site. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you (and our third party service providers may do so on our behalf). 

_Cookies._  
Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Site, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track your activities at our Site. There are two types of cookies: session and persistent cookies. 

  * _Session Cookies._ Session cookies exist only during an online session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser or turn off your computer. We use session cookies to allow our systems to uniquely identify you during a session or while you are logged into the Site. This allows us to process your online transactions and requests and verify your identity, after you have logged in, as you move through our Site.
  * _Persistent Cookies_. Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you have closed your browser or turned off your computer. We use persistent cookies to track aggregate and statistical information about user activity.

_Disabling Cookies_  
Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not function.

**Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies**  
Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs (a.k.a. web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our Site to, among other things, track the activities of Site visitors, help us manage content, and compile statistics about Site usage. We and our third party service providers also use clear GIFs in HTML emails to our users, to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed, and track whether our emails are forwarded.

**Third Party Analytics**  
We use automated devices and applications, such as Google Analytics, Crazy Egg, and Inspectlet to evaluate usage of our Site. We also may use other analytic means to evaluate our Services. We use these tools to help us improve our Site’s performance and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies, such as web beacons or local storage objects (LSOs), to perform their services. To learn more about Google’s privacy practices, please review the Google Privacy Policy at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>. You can also download the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on to prevent their data from being used by Google Analytics at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. If your personal Google Account settings permit Google to use your information to personalize advertisements, Google Analytics will use this information to identify other devices you use for advertising purposes. Please see the Cross-Device Use section below. To learn more, and to opt out of Crazy Egg, visit the [Crazy Egg Privacy Page](http://www.crazyegg.com/privacy). To learn more about Inspectlet’s privacy practices, visit the [Inspectlet Privacy Policy.](https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy)

**Cross-Device Use**  
We and our third party service providers, including Google, may use the information that we collect about you (whether directly from our Site, from our mobile applications, through your device(s), or from a third party) to help us and our third party service providers identify other devices that you use (e.g., a mobile phone, tablet, other computer, etc.). We, and our third party service providers also may use the cross-device use and other information we learn about you to serve targeted advertising on your devices and to send you emails. To opt-out of cross-device advertising, you may follow the instructions set forth in the Third Party Ad Networks/Social Networks section below. Please note: if you opt-out of these targeted advertising cookies, your opt-out will be specific to the web browser, app, or device from which you accessed the opt-out. If you use multiple devices or web browsers, you will need to opt-out each browser or device that you use.

**Do-Not-Track**  
Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” requests. You may, however, disable certain tracking as discussed in this section (e.g., by disabling cookies); you also may opt-out of targeted advertising by following the instructions in the Third Party Ad Network section.

**Third-Party Ad Networks**  
We use third parties such as network advertisers to serve advertisements on third-party websites or other media (e.g., social networking platforms). This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested. Third-party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), Flash LSOs and other tracking technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These third-party cookies and other technologies are governed by each third party’s specific privacy policy, not this one. We may provide these third-party advertisers with information, including personal information, about you. 

Users in the United States may opt out of many third-party ad networks. For example, you may go to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by [DAA companies.](http://www.aboutads.info/participating/) You may also go to the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) [Consumer Opt-Out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) Page for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by [NAI members](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

Opting out from one or more companies listed on the DAA [Consumer Choice](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN) Page or the NAI [Consumer Opt-Out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) Page will opt you out from those companies’ delivery of interest-based content or ads to you, but it does not mean you will no longer receive any advertising through our Site or on other websites. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing (i.e., contextually based ads). You will need to opt-out separately for each web browser and mobile device that you use. Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you opt out on the DAA or NAI websites, your opt out may not be effective. Additional information is available on the DAA’s website at [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) or the NAI’s website at www.networkadvertising.org.

**User Generated Content**  
We invite you to post content on our Site, including your comments, reviews, and any other information that you would like to be available on our Site. If you post content to our Site, all of the information that you post will be available to all visitors to our Site. If you post your own content on our Site, your posting may become public and Omron Healthcare cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy.

**Third-Party Links**  
Our Site may contain links to third-party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this Policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third party websites. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third party websites.

**Information Crossing Borders**  
For our Canadian users, please note that we may transfer your personal information across provincial or national borders to fulfil any of the purposes described above, including to service providers located in the United States and other jurisdictions outside of Canada who may be subject to applicable disclosure laws in those jurisdictions. You may contact us at the contact information is provided below to obtain information about our policies and practices regarding our transfer of data or use of service providers outside of Canada, or to ask questions about the collection, use, processing, disclosure or storage of personal information outside of Canada.

**Security of My Personal Information**  
We have implemented commercially reasonable precautions to protect the information we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware that despite our efforts, no data security measures can guarantee security.

You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your log-in and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity.

**Access To My Personal Information**  
You may modify personal information that you have submitted by logging into your account and updating your profile information. Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified or deleted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Site for a period of time.

Also, upon written request and authentication of identity, we will provide you with your other personal information under our control, information about the ways in which that information is being used and a description of the individuals and organizations to whom that information has been disclosed.

In some situations we may not be able to provide access to certain personal information. This may be the case where, for example, disclosure would reveal personal information about another individual, the information was collected for the purpose of an investigation or where disclosure of the information would reveal confidential commercial information that, if disclosed, could harm our competitive position. We may also be prevented by law from providing access to certain personal information. When an access request is refused, we will notify you in writing, document the reasons for refusal and outline further steps which are available to you.

We will make a reasonable effort to ensure that personal information we are using or disclosing is accurate and complete. In most cases, we rely on you to ensure that your information is current, complete and accurate.

If you demonstrate the inaccuracy or incompleteness of personal information, we will amend the information as required. If appropriate, we will send the amended information to third parties to whom the information has been disclosed. When a challenge regarding the accuracy of personal information is not resolved to your satisfaction, we will annotate the personal information under its control with a note that the correction was requested but not made.

**What Choices Do I Have Regarding Use of My Personal Information?**  
As permitted by law, and where required, with your consent, we may send periodic promotional emails to you. You may opt-out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the email. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If you opt-out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you emails about your account or any services you have requested or received from us.

You may also withdraw your consent to our collections, uses and disclosures of your information at any time, subject to legal, contractual and other restrictions, provided that you give us reasonable notice of your withdrawal of consent. When we receive notice of withdrawal of consent, we will inform you of the likely consequences of that withdrawal of consent, which may include our inability to provide certain services for which that information is necessary.

**Children Under 13**  
Our Site is not designed for children under 13. If we discover that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete such information from our systems.

**Special Information for California Consumers**  
California residents may request a list of certain third parties to which we have disclosed personally identifiable information about you for their own direct marketing purposes. You may make one request per calendar year. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response. You may request this information in writing by contacting us at: support@omronhealthcare.com. Please allow up to thirty (30) days for a response.

**Contact Us**  
If you have questions about the privacy aspects of our Services or would like to make a complaint, please contact us at our call center by calling 866.216.1333 or email us at support@omronhealthcare.com.

**Changes to this Policy**  
This Policy is current as of the Effective Date set forth above. We may change this Policy from time to time, so please be sure to check back periodically. We will post any changes to this Policy on our Site. If we make any changes to this Policy that materially affect our practices with regard to the personal information we have previously collected from you, we will endeavor to provide you with notice in advance of such change by highlighting the change on our Site.
